DAN KLEIN: Today we're going
to talk about constraint
satisfaction problems.
Let's take a step back and
think about search.
We've been talking about search
for the past lectures.
And let's think about
what search is for.
It needs to be that you've
got one agent.
So no adversary is trying
to mess you up.
You need to have deterministic
actions.
That means, when you come up with this
master plan that you're going to
execute and sequence, it better do
what you think it's going to do.
There can't be any uncertainty about
what your actions will actually
accomplish.
It's also for a fully observed state.
You need to know the entire state
of the world as relevant to
your planning problem.
And then we've also made an assumption
that the search space is discrete.
OK.
So that's the world of search, and
constraint satisfaction problems are
going to fall within that.
So let's think a little bit about what
a search problem looks like.
So, the search problems that we've
seen so far are primarily for
planning, and planning is about coming
up with a sequence of actions.
For example, how do I get to the exit
of the maze or what sequence of
pancake flips will be optimal.
The important thing in a planning
problem is that what you're looking
for is not the goal itself, but
the path that gets you there.
That's your plan.
It's the sequence of actions.
And in the context of planning, paths or
plans have various costs, they have
depths, and in order to speed up our
search, we use things like heuristics
and A* search which give us some
guidance about our specific problem.
OK, so the critical thing is, in a
planning problem, you're looking for a
sequence of actions.
There's another class of search problems
which we're going to start
thinking about today which are called
identification problems.
In an identification problem, what
you're really after is something like
assignments to variable.
You're looking for the goal itself.
So the idea is, once you find the goal
and you find some configuration of the
world that passes the goal
test, you're happy.
You don't actually care so
much how you got there.
So you can think about this in
terms of these cartoons.
A planning problem might be the ninja
robot trying to steal the gem, but an
identification problem, the detective
robot just wants to find it and
doesn't actually care the sequence
of places you looked in
order to get there.
OK.
In the case of an identification
problem, the goal is what's important.
It's very common that for some
formulation, all paths are going to be
at the same depth.
We'll see examples of that today.
And a particularly important case of
an identification problem is a
constraint satisfaction problem, or a
CSP, which is what we're going to talk
about today.
It's a special class for identification
problems where we'll
have special algorithms that
make things faster.